CONTROL [OVER RADIO]:
Please verify that the P1 ATA removal...
...on replacement cap part 1 and 2
are complete.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
DMA M1, M2, M3 and M4 are complete.
CONTROL:
Okay. Copy that, Explorer.
Dr. Stone, Houston.
Medical is concerned
about your ECG readings.
STONE [OVER RADIO]:
I'm fine, Houston.
CONTROL: Well, Medical doesn't agree,
doc. Are you feeling nauseous?
STONE: Not any more than usual, Houston.
Diagnostics are green.
Link to communications card
ready for data reception.
If this works, when we touch down tomorrow,
I'm buying all you guys a round of drinks.
CONTROL:
That's a date, doctor.
Just remember,
Houston's partial to margaritas.
STONE:
Booting comms card now.
Please confirm link.
CONTROL:
That's a negative, we're not seeing any data.
STONE". Stand by, Houston,
I'm gonna reboot the comms card.
CONTROL:
Standing by.
KOWALSKI [OVER RADIO]: Houston,
I have a bad feeling about this mission.
CONTROL:
Please expand.
KOWALSKI:
Okay, let me tell you a story.
It was '96. I'd been up here for 42 days.
Every time I passed over Texas,
I looked down...
...knowing that Mrs. Kowalski
was looking up, thinking of me.
Six weeks I'm blowing kisses at that woman.
Then we land at Edwards and I find out
that she's run off with this lawyer.
So I packed my car, and I headed to--
CONTROL:
Tijuana. You've told this story, Kowalski.
As Houston recalls,
she, uh, took off in your '74 GTO.
Engineering requests fuel status
on the jetpack prototype.
KOWALSKI: Five hours off the reservation
and I show 30 percent drain.
Give my compliments to Engineering.
Except for a slight malfunction
in the nulling of the roll axis...
...this jetpack is one prime piece of thrust.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
CONTROL:
Engineering says thank you.
KOWALSKI: Tell them I still prefer
my '67 Corvette, though.
- Speaking of which, did I ever tell you--
CONTROL: We know the Corvette story.
KOWALSKI:
Even Engineering?
CONTROL:
Especially Engineering.
We're going to miss you, Matt.
STONE:
Comms card reboot in progress.
CONTROL:
Thank you, doctor.
Sharif f, what's your status?
SHARIFF [OVER RADIO]: Nearly there.
Replacing battery module A 1 and C.
CONTROL:
Could you be a little more specific?
Indeterminate estimates
make Houston anxious.
SHARIFF:
No, no, no, Houston. Don't be anxious.
Anxiety's not good for the heart.
System is ready to reactivate.
CONTROL: Hubble telescope engaged.
Upgrade fully functional.
[APPLAUSE OVER RADIO]
That applause you hear is for you, Sharif f.
Congratulations.
Kick back, take the rest of the day off.
[SHARIFF LAUGHING]
[SHARIFF SINGING IN HINDI]
CONTROL:
Matt, do you have a visual...
...on just what Mission Specialist Sharif f
is doing up there?
He appears to be doing
some form of the Macarena.
But that would be just a best-guess scenario
on my part.
CONTROL:
Dr. Stone, Houston.
Medical now have you
with a temperature drop to 35. 9...
...and a heart-rate rise to 70.
How are you feeling?
STONE:
Houston, I'm fine.
It's just keeping your lunch down in zero-G
is harder than it looks.
CONTROL: Dr. Stone, Medical is asking
if you want to return to Explorer.
STONE: Negative. We've been here a week,
Houston. Let's just finish this. Ahem.
Card is up.
CONTROL:
No, that's a negative.
I'm afraid we're getting nothing
on this end, doctor.
Try again.
CONTROL:
No, still nothing.
Houston, can you please
turn that music off?
CONTROL:
Kowalski.
KOWALSKI:
Not a problem.
Thank you, Kowalski.
[MUSIC STOPS]
Now, Houston?
CONTROL:
That's a negative.
Could Houston be misinterpreting the data?
CONTROL:
Well, we're not receiving any data.
Engineering is recommending
a vis-check for component damage.
STONE:
Let me see what's going on.
What have we got?
Visual examination doesn't reveal
any damaged components.
The problem must be originating
from the comms panel.
CONTROL:
Yeah, that seems to be the case.
Engineering admits that you warned us
that this could happen.
That's as close to an apology
as you're going to get from them.
We should have listened to you, doc.
Well, looks like
we're going to have to improvise.
I'm on it.
CONTROL:
How long do you think it'll take you?
One hour. Ahem.
CONTROL:
Outstanding.
Installing your system in the Hubble
is the purpose of this mission...
...and so we appreciate
your patience, doctor.
Kowalski, we know you don't care
about things like this...
...but, uh, for your information,
this delay is not going to be long enough...
...for you to break Anatoly Solovyev's
spacewalking record.
- It seems like you're gonna be left--
KOWALSKI: Seventy-five minutes shy?
Never crossed my mind.
CONTROL:
Matt...
...it's been a privilege.
KOWALSKI:
Right back at you, Houston.
CONTROL:
Enjoy your last walk.
Am I a go to assist Dr. Stone
in removing the panel?
STONE". Assistance appreciated.
CONTROL". Permission granted.
KOWALSKI:
Thank you, Houston. Agh.
Mind if I join the fun?
Certainly.
KOWALSKI:
How you feeling?
Like a Chihuahua that's being tumble-dried.
Well, it's been a rough week.
If it makes you feel any better...
...I coughed up everything
but my kidneys on my first ride.
Shit.
Ah. Ah. Unh.
[CHUCKLES]
- Ha, ha.
- Sorry.
I'm used to a basement lab in a hospital
where things fall to the floor.
Thank you.
Well, you're the genius up here.
I only drive the bus.
Yeah, well, call me a genius...
...if I can get this board initialized
in the next hour.
CONTROL:
Explorer, this is Houston.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
Go ahead, Houston.
CONTROL: NORAD reports a Russian
satellite has incurred a missile strike.
The impact has created a cloud of debris...
...orbiting at 20,000 miles per hour.
Current debris orbit does not overlap
with your trajectory.
We'll keep you posted on any developments.
WOMAN:
Copy that, Houston.
Should we be worried?
No, let's let the boys down there
worry for us.
Explorer, engage arm and pivot
to cargo bay.
WOMAN:
Stand by for arm maneuver.
Aah.
So, doc, now that you work for NASA,
how do you like us?
SHARIFF:
Kind of like winning the lottery, huh?
I was just happy that they didn't cut
the funding to my research.
- How long was your training?
- Oh, six months.
SHARIFF: Including holidays?
STONE: Uh-huh.
So, what is this scanning system?
SHARIFF:
Oh, nothing, Matt.
It's just a new set of eyes
to scan the edge of the universe.
It's designed for hospital use,
but this one's a prototype.
WOMAN:
Stand by for locking.
STONE: Unh.
- Listen, they don't bankroll prototypes.
Even for your pretty blue eyes.
Well, my eyes are brown.
Right now, your eyes are bloodshot.
SHARI FF:
Kowalski! Is this great or what?
[LAUGHING]
And to think he went to Harvard.
You gotta admit one thing:
Can't beat the view.
So, what do you like about being up here?
STONE:
The silence.
I could get used to it.
[CHUCKLES]
Terrific.
STONE: Houston, from first inspection,
comms panel appears to be dead.
Am I a go to cut link to auxiliary?
CONTROL:
You're the expert, doctor. It's your call.
Houston, I have a bad feeling
about this mission.
CONTROL:
Please elaborate.
It's the same feeling I had
about Mardi Gras in 1987.
CONTROL:
That is affirmative.
Surprisingly, Control hasn't heard
the Mardi Gras story.
Please proceed.
Well, it's day one, and I'm bumping
my way down Bourbon Street...
...looking for a sister of a friend of mine.
Streets are full of people, I'm thinking
there's no way I'm gonna find this girl.
STONE:
Proceeding to override.
Then all of a sudden, I look up
and there she is. I'm about to yell out.
I see she's holding hands
with some hairy guy in board shorts...
...and a Margaritaville shirt.
And then I realize that this guy is not a guy.
That my girl is holding hands with--
CONTROL:
ISS, this is Houston.
- Explorer, this is Houston.
WOMAN: Go ahead, Houston.
CONTROL:
Mission abort. Repeat, mission abort.
Initiate emergency disconnect from Hubble.
Begin reentry procedure.
ISS, initiate emergency evacuation.
WOMAN:
Copy all, Houston, and in work.
Matt, immediate return to Explorer.
Repeat, immediate return to Explorer.
Copy. Explorer, prep airlock.
WOMAN: Airlock engaged, ready to receive.
- Houston, elaborate.
CONTROL". Debris from the missile strike
has caused a chain reaction...
...hitting other satellites
and creating new debris.
Traveling faster than a high-speed bullet
up towards your altitude. All copy.
Copy all.
Put a bow on it, Dr. Stone.
I can't. The board is still initializing.
- I'm not gonna ask you again.
- One second.
Not one second. Now. Shut it down.
That's an order.
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm done.
I'm done.
WOMAN: Kowalski, initiate emergency
disconnect from the Hubble.
- All right, Sharif f, let's do this.
SHARIFF: Roger, Matt.
KOWALSKI:
Houston, update.
CONTROL:
Well, we have a full-on chain reaction.
It's been confirmed
that it's the unintentional side effect...
...of the Russians striking
one of their own satellites.
SHARIFF: They shot down their own satellite?
- Right of disposal.
Most likely a spy sat gone bad.
Now it's shrapnel.
Explorer, ready to disengage HST.
WOMAN:
Locks releasing in three, two, one.
CONTROL:
Explorer, new data coming through.
KOWALSKI:
What's the blowback, Houston?
CONTROL:
It's not good. Most of our systems are gone.
Debris chain reaction is out of control
and rapidly expanding.
Multiple satellites are down
and they keep on falling.
Define "multiple satellites."
CONTROL:
Most of them are gone.
Telecommunication systems are dead.
Expect a communication blackout
at any moment.
STONE:
Kowalski, visual of debris at 9 o'clock.
Half of North America
just lost their Facebook.
CONTROL:
Explorer, repeat...
...expect a communication blackout
at any moment.
WOMAN:
Copy that, Houston.
KOWALSKI: Explorer, this is Kowalski,
confirming visual contact with debris.
Debris is from a BSE sat.
SHARIFF: Heads up!
KOWALSKI: To repeat, I have--
STONE: Dr. Stone requesting faster transport.
- We have to go. We have to go, go, go!
CONTROL: Kennedy reports
meteorological conditions no-go...
WOMAN:
Houston, Explorer. Copy.
STONE: Explorer, Dr. Stone requesting
faster transport to bay area.
Explorer, do you copy?
- Explorer, permission to retrieve Dr. Stone.
WOMAN: You're a go, Kowalski.
Houston, this is Explorer, copy.
KOWALSKI: All right.
WOMAN: We've lost Houston.
KOWALSKI: Unh!
Unstrap. Look, we need to
get the hell out of here.
SHARIFF: Need some help there, Matt?
- No, don't wait for us.
SHARIFF: Unh!
-It's stuck!
KOWALSKI:
Man down! Man down!
WOMAN: Houston, this is Explorer, copy.
STONE: Aah!
WOMAN:
Kowalski, repor--
[STONE YELLING]
KOWALSKI:
Explorer's been hit. Explorer, do you read?
Aah!
KOWALSKI:
Explorer, over. Explorer.
[STONE SCREAMS]
KOWALSKI: Astronaut is off structure.
Dr. Stone is off structure.
- Dr. Stone, detach! You must detach!
- No!
KOWALSKI: If you don't detach,
that arm's gonna carry you too far!
- Listen to my voice! You need to focus!
- I can't!
KOWALSKI: I'm losing visual of you.
In a few seconds I won't be able to track you.
You need to detach!
- I can't see you anymore. Do it now!
STONE: I'm trying! I'm trying!
[YELLS]
KOWALSKI:
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.
[STONE GASPING]
KOWALSKI:
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
Repeat, do you copy?
- Yes, yes, yes, I copy! I'm detached!
KOWALSKI: Give me your position.
I don't know! I don't know,
I'm spinning! I can't--!
KOWALSKI:
Report your position.
GPS is down. I can't-- It's down, I can't--
KOWALSKI: Give me a visual.
- I told you, nothing. I see nothing!
KOWALSKI: Do you have a visual of Explorer?
- No.
KOWALSKI: Do you have a visual of ISS?
KOWALSKI: You need to focus. Anything, use
the sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.
- I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
KOWALSKI: Give me coordinates!
[GASPING]
KOWALSKI:
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
[CONTINUES GASPING]
Kowalski? Kowalski, do you copy?
Kowals-- I have a vis--
Kowalski, I have a visual.
I have a visual of Explorer.
With north at 12 o'clock...
...and the shuttle is at the center of the dial.
I can see the Chinese station.
No, it's the International Space Station.
ISS is at...
ISS is at 7 o'clock.
Lieutenant Kowalski, do you copy?
Explorer, do you copy?
Houston, do you copy?
Houston, this is
Mission Specialist Ryan Stone.
I am off structure and I am drifting.
Do you copy?
Anyone...?
anybody- - -?
Do you copy?
Please copy.
Please.
KOWALSKI:
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
STONE: Yeah, Lieutenant Kowalski, yes.
Yes, Lieutenant Kowalski, I'm here!
KOWALSKI: Repeat, do you copy?
STONE: Yes, yes, I copy, I'm here. I'm here.
KOWALS Kl :
Flash your light.
STONE: My light?
KOWALSKI: Flash it so I can see you.
STONE:
Okay.
[PANTING]
Okay, okay. Here, here! I'm here!
KOWALSKI:
There you are. Hang on tight.
Report your status.
STONE:
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm all right.
KOWALSKI:
Your status. Give me your readings.
STONE:
Three... Three...
Three-point-six PSI.
KOWALSKI:
Your O2, give me your O2.
STONE: Oxygen is going down. It's going
down fast. It's going down fast. Nine--
No, 8 percent.
KOWALSKI:
You're breathing too fast.
You're burning oxygen,
and we don't wanna do that.
We wanna relax. Copy?
STONE:
Okay, sorry. Yes, copy.
KOWALSKI: All right. Nearly there.
- Copy. Please hurry.
KOWALSKI:
You can holster that torch, Dr. Stone.
Sorry. Sorry.
- Aah!
- Gotcha.
All right, now I'm gonna tether you to me.
I know, you never realized
how devastatingly good-looking I am.
But I need you to stop staring
and help me with the tether.
Okay?
STONE:
Okay. Okay.
Uh, I got it.
All right, here we go.
Now, to clear you from the jets,
I'm gonna give you a little push.
- No, no, no.
- Not a push.
A nudge.
No, no, no! Damn it, no!
[PANTING]
[BOTH GRUNT]
See? Where you go, I go.
[CHUCKLES]
Better.
Let's get out of here.
- Goddamn it! Agh.
- I know what you mean.
STONE:
Damn it.
KOWALSKI:
You're burning oxygen.
We're going back to the shuttle.
How's that for a plan? Copy?
STONE:
Fuck!
KOWALSKI:
Right. Copy that.
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
Dr. Stone and I are gonna
make our way back to base.
Can you get the Explorer to prepare
the airlock for arrival? Copy?
Houston, this is Kowalski.
How do you copy?
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
STONE:
They can't hear us.
KOWALSKI: We don't know that.
That's why we keep talking.
If somebody is listening,
they might just save your life.
Set your watch for 90 minutes.
- Why 90?
KOWALSKI: Houston clocked that debris...
...at 50,000 miles an hour.
If you factor in our current orbit...
...then I figure we got about 90 minutes
before we get our asses kicked again.
STONE:
O2 down to 6 percent.
KOWALSKI: Okay. Pretty scary shit
being untethered up here, isn't it?
Yeah, pretty scary shit.
Well, you did all right.
[GRUNTS]
STONE:
Well, you weren't so bad yourself.
KOWALSKI:
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
Our current location is approximately...
...900 meters out from the Explorer.
Dr. Stone and I would like to
retrieve the body...
...of Mission Specialist Sharif f...
...and return it to the shuttle.
Am I a go to retrieve?
Roger that.
STONE:
Where is he? Where is he?
[GASPING]
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
KOWALSKI:
Grab him!
Grab him! Agh!
STONE:
I'm trying, I'm trying!
KOWALSKI:
You're pulling me away.
STONE:
I got him!
KOWALSKI: Clutch him like he's your valentine.
- I got him.
I can't engage my thrust
with you two yo-yoing around.
KOWALSKI:
Jesus Christ.
Here's hoping you have a hell
of an insurance policy, Houston.
The damages to Explorer...
...are catastrophic.
Will commence search for survivors.
STONE:
O2 down to 5 percent.
KOWALSKI:
All right, here we go. Careful of the edges!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
KOWALSKI:
Here. Here!
[YELLS]
Houston, in the blind. To confirm:
Mission Specialist Dr. Stone and
Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski...
...are the sole survivors of the STS-157.
I apologize for not complying.
I should've stopped working
as soon as you instructed me to.
We were gonna get hit no matter what.
There was nothing you could do
to change that.
Hey-
Yes?
All right...
...we have to make our way
to the space station.
Over there.
It's a bit of a hike...
...but we need to use their escape pod,
the Soyuz, to get back to Earth.
Agreed?
Dr. Stone...
...agreed?
Agreed.
All right. After you.
Oh, God.
[BOTH GRUNT]
KOWALSKI:
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
Dr. Stone and I have determined
to proceed to ISS...
...and use one of their Soyuz for reentry.
ISS, if you hear us...
...we could sure use a rescue mission.
STONE:
O2 down to 2 percent.
KOWALSKI:
We're getting there.
Beautiful, don't you think?
STONE:
What?
KOWALSKI:
The sunrise.
That's what I'm gonna miss the most.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
So where's home, Dr. Stone?
Ryan, where's home?
- Home?
- Mm-hm.
Down there. Mother Earth.
Where do you pitch your tent?
Lake Zurich.
Where the hell is that?
Illinois.
Illinois. Central time zone.
That would make it roughly...
...8 p.m.
What are the good people of Lake Zurich
doing at 8:00?
I don't know.
I'm not gonna make it.
I'm slowing you down.
What would you be doing?
Come on, Ryan.
It's 8200.
You've just left the hospital
after an 18-hour shift.
Driving home.
The radio.
I listen to the radio.
There we go. Let me guess.
NPR?
Classical?
Ton 40?
Anything. I don't care,
as long as they don't talk. I just drive.
And where are you driving to?
I just drive.
What do you miss down there?
Is there a Mr. Stone?
No.
Nobody special?
Somebody down there looking up...
...thinking about you?
Ryan?
I had a daughter.
[MUSIC STOPS]
She was 4.
She was at school playing tag.
Slipped, hit her head, and that was it.
Stupidest thing.
I was driving when I got the call, so...
Ever since then, that's what I do.
I wake up...
...I go to work...
...and I just drive.
O2 down to 1 percent.
KOWALSKI:
Well, I've got good news and bad news.
The good news is, we're about 5 minutes
from the ISS...
...and I know where the Russians
stash their vodka.
And that is good,
because I'm running on fumes here.
The bad news is...
...I'm gonna be about 10 minutes short
of breaking Anatoly's record, and--
[DEVICE BEEPING]
STONE: Agh!
- What?
I'm redlining. My O2 tank pressure is low.
Your tank is out of oxygen,
but you still have it in your suit.
Got it.
KOWALSKI:
So you have to sip, not gulp.
Wine, not beer.
Sip, Ryan.
Houston, in the blind,
we have a visual of the ISS.
The station must have been evacuated
because the first Soyuz...
...is missing. The second Soyuz
exhibits surface damage...
...and its chute has been deployed.
Any use as an escape pod for reentry
is impossible.
STONE: Shouldn't we be turning?
We're drifting again.
KOWALSKI: Not yet.
I wasn't kidding about those fumes.
This can has one or two good thrusts left...
...if we're lucky.
Steady.
Aim.
Fire.
[STONE GASPING]
- Brake! Brake. You have to brake!
- I can't, the can's...
...empty. We're gonna hit hard.
Grab ahold of anything you can!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
STONE:
What do I do?
Ryan!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
STONE: The tether broke, I'm detached!
I'm detached!
KOWALSKI:
Grab ahold!
Grab anything!
[GASPING]
KOWALSKI:
Ryan!
- Give me five.
- I've got you.
I've got you. Right here.
[BOTH GRUNT]
Shit!
STONE:
No,no,no!
Got you.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
You just hold on,
and I'm gonna start pulling you in.
Hey, doc.
Just hold on. Hang on.
- I am gonna pull you in.
- Ryan, listen.
You have to let me go.
- No.
- The ropes are too loose.
I'm pulling you with me.
- Let me go or we both die.
- I'm not letting you go!
We're fine! Unh.
- Agh!
- No.
[BOTH GRUNT]
KOWALSKI:
Ryan, let go.
STONE:
No. No.
You're not going anywhere.
-It's not up to you.
- No, no, no.
Please don't do this.
Please, please, please. Please don't do this.
Please don't do this. No, no, no.
Please don't, Matt.
Please don't do this.
You're gonna make it, Ryan.
No!
I had you. I had you. I had you.
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
[DEVICE BEEPING]
KOWALSKI:
Ryan, do you hear me?
Do you copy?
My CO2 alarm went off.
KOWALSKI:
Look, you need to board the station.
Do you see the airlock?
Hey, Ryan.
You COPY?
Look for the airlock.
It's above you, next to the Zarya module.
You see it?
STONE:
Yes. Yes, I see it. I see it.
KOWALSKI:
All right, good. That's where you wanna go.
Now you're getting light-headed, right?
Yeah. Yes.
KOWALSKI:
That's because you're breathing CO2.
You're losing consciousness.
You need to board the station.
Okay.
KOWALSKI: That second Soyuz
is too damaged for reentry...
...but it's perfectly fine
for a little Sunday drive.
Sunday drive?
KOWALSKI:
Look to the west.
You see that dot in the distance?
That's a Chinese station.
STONE:
Yes.
KOWALSKI: You're gonna take the Soyuz,
and you're gonna cruise over there.
Chinese lifeboat is a Shenzhou.
I've never flown a Shenzhou.
KOWALSKI:
It doesn't matter.
Its reentry protocol is identical to the Soyuz.
Okay.
KOWALSKI:
You never flown the Soyuz either?
Only a simulator.
KOWALSKI:
Well, then you know.
But I crashed it.
KOWALSKI:
It's a simulator, that's what it's designed for.
Every time.
I crashed it every time.
KOWALSKI: You point the damn thing
at Earth. It's not rocket science.
And by this time tomorrow, you're gonna be
back in Lake Zurich with a hell of a story to tell.
You COPY?
Ryan, you copy?
- I'm gonna take the Soyuz and come get you.
KOWALSKI: No, you're not.
- I'm coming to get you.
KOWALSKI: I've got too much of a head start.
KOWALSKI: I'm afraid that ship already sailed.
Ryan, you're gonna have to learn to let go.
- But I--
KOWALSKI: I wanna hear you say...
...you're gonna make it.
Come on, Ryan, say it.
I'm gonna make it.
KOWALSKI:
All right. Keep going.
What kind of a name is Ryan for a girl?
Dad wanted a boy.
KOWALSKI:
Are you close to the airlock?
Not yet.
KOWALSKI:
Keep going.
So now that we have some distance
between us...
...you're attracted to me, right?
What?
KOWALSKI:
Well, people say I have beautiful blue eyes.
You have beautiful--
You have beautiful blue eyes.
KOWALSKI:
I have brown eyes.
Hey, you wanna know the good news?
What?
KOWALSKI:
I'm gonna break Anatoly's record...
...and I think mine's
gonna stand for a long, long time.
Oh, no. I'm coming to get you.
KOWALSKI:
Oh, my God.
What? What?
KOWALSKI:
Wow.
Hey, Ryan?
Yeah?
KOWALSKI:
You should see the sun on the Ganges.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
It's amazing.
[GASPING]
[GRUNTING]
Where are you? Where are you?
Comms. Comms.
There you are. Okay.
Matt, this is Ryan, copy.
Matt, I made it, I'm here,
I'm on the station. Do you copy?
Come on, Matt, talk to me.
Tell me where you are,
give me your position.
Where are you? Give me a visual.
Just tell me what you see.
Oh, come on. You've been yammering
since we left Cape Canaveral.
Now you decide to shut up? Talk to me.
Just say something, say anything.
I don't care.
Hey-
Tell me about, uh, Mardi Gras.
Tell me about the hairy guy.
Huh? Tell me what happened.
What happened to the, uh, hairy guy?
Please talk to me.
Please.
Houston, in the blind...
...this is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone
reporting from the ISS.
All communications with
Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski...
...have been lost.
Radio transmission absent.
Visuals nonexistent.
To confirm...
...l, Ryan Stone, am the sole survivor...
...of STS-157.
[ALARM WAILING]
What now?
[GRUNTING]
Agh.
[GROANING]
[YELLING]
[EXPLOSION]
Okay.
Okay. Where is it, where is it?
Where is the power? Here you are.
Okay, great, just like training.
Undocking, undocking.
Undocking.
Red.
Okay.
Okay, where is it?
Where is it?
[RUMBLING]
Come on.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, I remember this.
I remember this.
[BANGING]
Oh, you don't have four minutes.
We're going manual.
Come on.
Okay.
Okay. Activate- Activate undock.
[MUTTERING]
Seven minutes to get out of here.
All right, okay.
[GRUNTS]
[ALARM WAILING]
What? What, what?
No, no, no!
Unh! Agh.
Stop, stop, Stop!
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
That's right, that's right.
Come on, come on.
That's right, that's right, that's right.
Ahh.
Come on.
[BEEPING CONTINUES]
[BEEPING STOPS]
Great.
[BREATHING STEADILY]
[DEVICE BEEPS]
Clear skies with a chance of satellite debris.
[HUMMING QUIETLY]
Okay, we detach this and we go home.
Piece of cake.
Okay.
Okay, what do we have?
Okay, all right.
Shit.
Okay, come on.
Come on, come on.
All right.
[CONTINUES HUMMING]
[GRUNTING]
[YELLING]
I hate space.
[BEEPING RAPIDLY]
[GROANING]
Shut up.
Okay.
All right.
That's good.
Okay.
Let's stabilize you.
Let's go visit the Chinese station.
Houston, in the blind...
Tiangong is approximately
100 kilometers...
...to the west...
...and I am off its course by about...
...13 degrees.
I will correct trajectory.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Okay.
I will engage S-Ka-Dae...
...in five, four, three...
...two, one.
What's happening, what's happening?
Come on, come on.
One.
Come on, come OH, come on.
You gotta be kidding me.
You gotta be kidding me!
[YELLING]
No! Don't you fu--
Houston, in the blind.
Houston, in the blind,
this is Dr. Ryan Stone.
I'm calling from the Soyuz TMA-14M.
I'm currently out of fuel and adrift,
do you copy?
Houston. This is Dr. Ryan Stone.
Do you copy?
Houston. This is Ryan Stone.
Houston, this is Mission--
Mission Specialist Ryan Stone.
Do you copy?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER RADIO]
STONE:
Houston. Houston, please confirm identity.
Houston, you're coming in
over an AM frequency. Copy.
Do you copy?
Is this the Chinese station?
Is this Tiangong? Copy.
[CHATTER CONTINUES]
STONE:
Mayday, can you copy?
Mayday, mayday. Mayday.
MAN [OVER RADIO]: Mayday.
- Yes, yes. Mayday, mayday.
MAN: Mayday.
- Mayday, mayday.
MAN:
Aningaaq.
[MAN SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- Aningaaq, is that your name?
MAN: Aningaaq.
- Aningaaq is your name? Is that your name?
MAN: Mayday. Aningaaq.
Aningaaq. mayday-
No, no, no. No, my name is not mayday.
I'm Stone. Dr. Ryan Stone.
I need help. I am--
[BARKING OVER RADIO]
Those are dogs.
They're calling from Earth.
[MAN SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- They're calling from Earth.
MAN: Ha-ha-ha!
[MAN CONTINUES SPEAKING
AND STONE GROANS]
Aningaaq...
...make your dogs bark again for me,
would you, please?
[MAN SPEAKING]
Your dogs. Dogs, you know.
MAN: Ha-ha-ha!
- Woof, woof. Dogs.
[MAN MIMICKING DOG BARKING]
[HOWLING]
[MAN LAUGHING]
[BOTH HOWLING]
Woof, woof.
[BOTH CONTINUE HOWLING]
Oh, I'm gonna die, Aningaaq.
I know, we're all gonna die.
Everybody knows that.
But I'm gonna die today.
Funny, that.
You know, to know...
But the thing is, it's that I'm still scared.
I'm really scared.
Nobody will mourn for me,
no one will pray for my soul.
Will you mourn for me?
Will you say a prayer for me?
Or is it too late?
[SIGHS]
I mean, I'd say one for myself,
but I've never prayed in my life, so...
Nobody ever taught me how.
[MAN SPEAKING]
[BABY CRYING OVER RADIO]
A baby.
[MAN CONTINUES SPEAKING]
[MAN SINGING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
There's a baby with you, huh?
Is that a lullaby you're singing?
[BABY comma]
That's so sweet.
I used to sing to my baby.
I hope I see her soon.
[MAN CONTINUES SINGING]
[ALARM WAILING]
That's nice, Aningaaq.
Keep singing, just like that.
Sing me to sleep, and I'll sleep.
Keep singing. And sing and sing.
[KNOCKING ON WINDOW]
No, no, no, don't!
Check your watch.
Thirteen hours and 11 minutes.
Call Anatoly and tell him he's been bumped.
-It's a little gloomy in here, isn't it?
- How did you--?
- Trust me, it's a hell of a story.
- But how did you--?
[GRUNTS]
That's better.
I found a little extra--
A little extra battery power.
It helps that I didn't have you around
to distract me.
I have to say, I'm glad to see you.
I didn't think you were gonna make it.
Did you find the vodka?
- You never told me where it was, so...
- Oh, well...
Ah, ah!
[BOTH SIGH]
To Anatoly.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
Huh? No? All right.
Let's get out of here.
The Chinese station's about 100 miles.
Just a little Sunday drive.
- We can't.
- Sure we can.
- There's no fuel, I tried everything.
- Well, there's always something we can do.
I tried everything.
Did you try the soft landing jets?
They're for landing, so...
Landing is launching. It's the same.
Didn't you learn that in training?
- I never got to land the simulator, I told you.
- But you know about it.
- And I crashed it every time.
- Do you wanna go back or stay here?
I get it, it's nice up here.
You can just shut down all the systems...
...turn out all the lights...
...and just close your eyes
and tune out everybody.
There's nobody up here that can hurt you.
It's safe.
I mean, what's the point of going on?
What's the point of living?
Your kid died.
Doesn't get any rougher than that.
But still, it's a matter of what you do now.
If you decide to go,
then you gotta just get on with it.
Sit back, enjoy the ride.
You gotta plant both your feet
on the ground and start living life.
How did you get here?
I'm telling you, it's a hell of a story.
Hey, Ryan?
What?
It's time to go home.
[ALARM STOPS]
[PANTING]
Landing...
Landing... Landing is launching.
I said...
[GROANS]
Okay, landing, landing.
Landing is green.
Agh.
Okay.
Okay, landing. All right.
Okay. Soft landing jets
trigger automatically...
...at 3 meters before landing, so...
Oh, you're a clever son of a bitch, Matt.
I need to... I need to get rid of the Bay-O...
...and the engine module.
Right. Okay.
Okay.
Tri-module separation.
Go.
Okay.
Houston, here's the tricky part.
Soyuz has to think...
...we are 3 meters off the Earth.
All right. Okay.
Hey, Matt?
Since I had to listen to endless hours...
...of your storytelling this week,
I need you to do me a favor.
You are gonna see
a little girl with brown hair...
...very messy, lots of knots.
She doesn't like to brush it.
That's okay.
Her name is Sarah.
Can you please tell her...
...that Mama found her red shoe?
She was so worried about that shoe, Matt.
But it was just right under the bed.
Give her...
...a big hug and a big kiss for me
and tell her that Mama misses her.
You tell her that she is my angel.
And she makes me so proud. So, so proud.
And you tell her that I'm not quitting.
You tell her that I love her, Matt.
You tell her that I love her so much.
Can you do that for me?
Roger that.
Here we go.
You're losing altitude, Tiangong.
You keep dropping
and you're gonna kiss the atmosphere.
But not without me
because you're my last ride.
Wait.
Five.
Four.
Three...
No more just driving.
Let's go home.
Okay, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Steady, steady.
Come on. Come on. Agh!
[GRUNTING]
Where are you? Where are you?
Forty-five, 90, 180.
One-eighty.
Agh!
Come on.
[GRUNTS]
Okay.
Damn it. Agh!
[GRUNTING]
Agh!
[MEN CHATTERING IN CHINESE]
[STONE GRUNTING]
[BANGING]
Shit!
Shenzhou, come on.
Shenzhou.Shenzhou.
Fuck!
Okay, this way.
[MAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE OVER RADIO]
[STONE GRUNTS]
In the Soyuz, the power button is...
...here.
Okay, uh, undocking, undocking. Um--
Uh, eenie, meenie--
[BEEPING RAPIDLY]
Okay, that doesn't sound good.
Minie...
...mo.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE
ON RECORDING]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Minie...
...mo.
Okay. Okay, good.
Houston. Houston, in the blind.
This is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone
reporting from the Shenzhou.
I'm about to undock from Tiangong.
Uh...
And I have a bad feeling
about this mission. Ha, ha.
Reminds me of a story, Houston. Aah!
[YELLING]
Never-- Never mind the story, Houston.
Never mind the story.
It's getting hot in here. Okay. All right.
Okay.
All right, the way I see it...
...there's only two possible outcomes.
Either I make it down there in one piece...
...and I have one hell of a story to tell...
...or I burn up in the next 10 minutes.
Aah.
Either way, whichever way...
...no harm, no foul! Aah!
[LAUGHS]
Because either way...
...it'll be one hell of a ride.
I'm ready.
[GRUNTING]
[BEEPING RAPIDLY]
CONTROL:
Shenzhou, in the blind...
...this is Houston. Indicate FM frequency.
Our radars detect you on a reentry trajectory.
If you copy, please confirm identity.
This is Houston...
[COUGHING]
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
CONTROL:
Please confirm identity.
MAN 1: Skies over the Midwest
are completely clear--
[MAN 2 SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
CONTROL:
Rescue mission is on the way.
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.
[COUGHING]
We've deployed a rescue mission--
Our radar--
[CONTINUES COUGHING]
[GASPING]
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
Thank you.
No.
[LAUGHING]
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Three, two...
...one, mark.
[English - US - SDH]
COLORED SUB BY EJSUB